Masum Billah



masum.billah78@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/mbillah-cse



+8801922483273



https://masumbillah.github.io/portfolio



Summary

Experienced Web Development with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Javascript, Jquery, Node js, Express js, Mongo db, Postgresql, React js, Vue.js, Angular Js, Meteor js, Node js, Laravel, Mysgl, Mongodb, graphql, Apollo client, Github, Bitbucket, AWS service, Rest API, etc. Strong engineering professional graduated from Dhaka International University.

Experience



Sr. Full-stack Developer

Battery Low Interactive Ltd.

Jan 2021 - Present (2 years 9 months)

Here, my responsibility is full-stack development. Basically I'm working with Node js, Express js, Postgresgl, Mongo DB, PHP latest framework Laravel, Mysgl, Vue js, Vuetify, React js, Angular js, aws services, firebase etc.

Implement applications:

- 01. Frontend, Backend and rest api(every things) of https://togumogu.com/
- 02. Frontend & Backend of https://motorcycles.runnerautomobiles.com, https://runnermotors.com.bd 03.

Frontend, Backend and rest api(every things) of https://send-dev.buddyandselly.com

- 04. Frontend, Backend and rest api(every things) of https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd
- 05. Completed Some our govt. private applications. It's govt's secret applications

All projects here work section https://masumbillah.github.io/portfolio

Sr. Web Developer

Gain Solutions Ltd

Oct 2014 - Dec 2020 (6 years 3 months)

I worked here javascript, node js, react js, react hooks, redux, vue js. Meteor js, Mongo db. Graphql and

01. Gain CRM - Now it's closed

02. Uniteliving - It's a property management system application.

https://uniteliving.com/



Executive of TV News

Ryans Computers Ltd.

Jan 2010 - Apr 2014 (4 years 4 months)

My responsibility was TV News monitor and reporting

Education

Dhaka International University

BSc in CSE 2009 - 2013

Jhenaidah Polytechnic Institute, Jhenaidah

Diploma in CSE 2005 - 2009

Skills

JavaScript • React.js • Node.js • Vue.js • Git • Laravel • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Honors & Awards



Employee of the Month - Bizzntek Ltd.

Feb 2023

Employee of the Year - Battery Low Interactive Ltd.

Jan 2022